Well, this is it.
It's time to develop our very first game.
And don't worry, we'll keep it simple.
But you will develop some core programming skills while making this game.
So as mentioned previously, the game we're going to build is quite simple, but it should be fun.
Basically, we're going to have a dragonfly and a ladybug sprite as the players, and you're going to
be able to control the dragonflies movement with your arrows, and the ladybug is just going to run
around the screen while we try and catch it.
We're also going to set the scene with a nice jungle background.
Okay, so now that we know what our game is and the sprites and background we need, I want you to import
the two sprites into the project and choose an appropriate backdrop.
So pause this video and do that.
Well if you manage that, well done.
So for this step, all we are doing is adding two sprites and a backdrop.
So for our sprites we can just click this Add Sprite button and search for dragonfly and just click
it.
You will see how it added to the project.
Again, we can do the same thing for the ladybug.
Okay.
And finally, we can add in our jungle backdrop by clicking this button instead.
And if you search jungle, you will find it right here.
So there you have it.
The stage is set and we have all the assets we need to make our game.
And before we continue to write some code for our sprites, I just want you to think about the process
we went through.
Because when programming, a very important part is thinking about the bigger picture, which in our
case is this game.
And after we know exactly what we want to make, we need to think about what we need to make this game.
Well, here, all we need are these two sprites and a nice background, but it's all about understanding
the bigger picture of what we want to do and breaking it down into smaller, manageable steps.
For example, let's say you want to build a tree house in your backyard.
Instead of trying to construct it all at once, you can break the project down into smaller steps,
like gathering the materials and measuring and cutting wood, building the frame, adding walls and
a roof, and then decorating the interior.
By doing this, you can make the project more manageable and less overwhelming, and ensure that you
build a safe and sturdy tree house that you can enjoy for years to come.
And the same is true with programming.
Well, pretty much everything in life.
But that's it for now.
We are ready to start bringing these sprites to life with code.